<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?><riskFactorAnalysis><text>Rev. 1.0
POWER GENERATION
MACHINERY UNDERWRITING SURVEY
Prepared for:
Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings
Canal Generating Plant Unit 3
9 Freezer Road
Sandwich, MA 02563
April 25, 2019
Attention:
Prepared by:
Ian Cowen
Senior Machinery Engineer
1 Meadowlands Plaza
East Rutherford, New Jersey 07073
Email: IanCowen@aegislimited.com
A-8721
AEGIS and the AEGIS logo are registered trademarks Solutions for Success of Associated Electric &amp; Gas Insurance Services Limited
Rev. 1.0
Mr. Sheldon McCaman
Underwriting Officer
Mr. Julian Zizak
Sr. Account Engineer
Prepared by:
Ian Cowen
Senior Machinery Engineer
1 Meadowlands Plaza
East Rutherford, New Jersey 07073
Email: IanCowen@aegislimited.com
A-8721
AEGIS and the AEGIS logo are registered trademarks Solutions for Success of Associated Electric &amp; Gas Insurance Services Limited
Table of Contents
Scope 1
Executive Summary 2
Risk Reduction Suggestions 3
General Plant Information 4
Risk Characteristics Ratings 6
Major Equipment 7
Boilers 7
Steam Turbines 9
Combustion Turbine 14
Generators 16
Transformers 18
Major Systems 20
High Energy Piping 20
Feedwater and Condensate 20
Water Treatment 20
Operations 21
Control Room Review 21
Operating Procedures 21
Operator Training 21
Operational Testing 21
Maintenance 23
Maintenance Management 23
Maintenance Training 23
Predictive Maintenance (PdM) 23
Pressure Vessels 23
Auxiliary Safety Valve Maintenance 23
Electrical Maintenance 23
Emergency Battery 23
Loss History 24
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 3Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Loss Estimates 25
Probable Maximum Loss (PML) 25
Maximum Foreseeable Loss (MFL) 25
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 4Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Scope
The intent of this Machinery Underwriting Survey is to evaluate the critical plant equipment located at this facility with regard to operations and maintenance. Evaluations are risk-based with emphasis on the human element aspects of the loss control programs.
It is understood that each facility has its own specific conditions that characterize its design and operating procedures. Generally, national and industry recognized standards are the basis for the evaluation and suggestions. This is not to preclude a professional’s qualified judgment when evaluating the adequacy of existing programs.
Conferred With
Mr. Jeffrey Araujo Plant Manager, NAES
Mr. James Lyon Operations Manager, NAES
Mr. Kyle Farrell Maintenance Manager, NAES
Mr. Scott Kerrigan V.P., Controller, Ironclad Energy Partners LLC
Mr. Martin J. Collins Senior V.P. of Acquisitions &amp; Asset Optimization,
Ironclad Energy Partners LLC
THE PURPOSE OF THIS ASSESSMENT IS TO EVALUATE AND DOCUMENT THE CURRENT
PROPERTY LOSS CONTROL PROGRAM, IDENTIFY RISKS AND SIGNIFICANT EXPOSURES
AND OFFER SUGGESTIONS ON POTENTIAL RISK REDUCTIONS. ANY OTHER USE OF THIS
ASSESSMENT, INCLUDING ANY ORAL OR WRITTEN DISCUSSION OR EXPLANATION OF
SAME, SHALL SIGNIFY THE USER’S ACKNOWLEDGEMENT AND AGREEMENT THAT
NEITHER ASSOCIATED ELECTRIC &amp; GAS INSURANCE SERVICES LIMITED NOR AEGIS
INSURANCE SERVICES, INC. HAS MADE ANY REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY WITH
RESPECT TO THIS REPORT AND THAT THE USER WAIVES ANY CLAIMS AGAINST AEGIS
AND/OR AEGIS SERVICES ARISING IN ANY WAY FROM THE USER’S USE OF THE REPORT.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 5Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
THE PURPOSE OF THIS ASSESSMENT IS TO EVALUATE AND DOCUMENT THE CURRENT
PROPERTY LOSS CONTROL PROGRAM, IDENTIFY RISKS AND SIGNIFICANT EXPOSURES
AND OFFER SUGGESTIONS ON POTENTIAL RISK REDUCTIONS. ANY OTHER USE OF THIS
ASSESSMENT, INCLUDING ANY ORAL OR WRITTEN DISCUSSION OR EXPLANATION OF
SAME, SHALL SIGNIFY THE USER’S ACKNOWLEDGEMENT AND AGREEMENT THAT
NEITHER ASSOCIATED ELECTRIC &amp; GAS INSURANCE SERVICES LIMITED NOR AEGIS
INSURANCE SERVICES, INC. HAS MADE ANY REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY WITH
RESPECT TO THIS REPORT AND THAT THE USER WAIVES ANY CLAIMS AGAINST AEGIS
AND/OR AEGIS SERVICES ARISING IN ANY WAY FROM THE USER’S USE OF THE REPORT.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 6Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Executive Summary
A Machinery Underwriting Survey was performed for the Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC, Canal
Generating Station located at 9 Freezer Road, Sandwich, MA 02563 on April 25, 2019.
Canal Generating Station is located in Sandwich, MA on Cape Cod. The plant is owned by Ironclad
Energy Partners LLC, which is majority owned by Stonepeak Infrastructure Fund II. The plant is operated by NAES a large O&amp;M services company operating ~ 150 facilities in the power generation, oil and gas and petrochemical industries.
A tour of the premises was conducted, including a review of observed risks, protective systems, maintenance practices and procedures, management programs and operator training. Plant personnel were interviewed to determine operating and maintenance practices at the location.
This visit was conducted as part of an insurance industry site tour. Many of the details reported during a typical AEGIS machinery assessment are therefore not available.
Significant Changes
No significant changes were reported.
Major Equipment – Overall rated Good. The major equipment is in generally good condition.
Major Systems – Overall rated Good. The major systems have historically been in good condition. A comprehensive HEP program is in place.
Operations – Overall rated Fair. The saltwater incursion incident revealed a number of shortcomings related to operations. NAES have since taken over the plant operations.
Maintenance – Overall rated Fair. Recent losses indicate that maintenance may not have been a priority at the plant. NAES have indicated that maintenance spending will be a significant factor of the ongoing budget.
Risk Reduction Suggestions
No new risk reduction suggestions were made as a result of this risk assessment.
Assessment Summary
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 7Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
With all areas combined, equipment conditions were found to be Good for machinery insurance purposes. Please refer to the Risk Characteristics Ratings section of this report for details.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 8Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Risk Reduction Suggestions
Risk Reduction Suggestions represent opportunities for continued improvement. The suggestions are risk-based and customized to this facility. The suggestions are made using national and industry recognized standards and recommended practices.
ProbabilityBased on historic information provided by recognized industry organizations and AEGIS loss experience
High (H) The probability of a loss is greater than average
Medium (M) The probability of a loss is average
Low (L) The probability of a loss is less than average
Severity Based on insurable values, deductibles and AEGIS loss experience
Severe (S) The incident may result in significant financial impact to the facility
Moderate (M) The incident may result in moderate financial impact to the facility
Low (L) The incident may result in low to moderate financial impact to the facility
Priority Matrix
H P3 P2 P1 y t i l i b a b M P4 P3 P2 o r
P
L P5 P4 P3
L M S
Severity
P1 – P2 – HIGH P3 – MODERATE P4 ? LOW P5 – SUPPLEMENTAL
CRITICAL
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 9Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
No new risk reduction suggestions were made as a result of this risk assessment.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 10Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
General Plant Information
Canal Units 1 and 2
Canal Unit 3 under construction
Plant Description
Canal Generating Station is located in Sandwich, MA on Cape Cod. The plant is managed by Ironclad
Energy Partners LLC, which is majority owned by Stonepeak Infrastructure Fund II. The plant is operated by NAES a large O&amp;M services company which operates ~ 150 facilities in the power
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 11Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station generation, oil and gas and petrochemical industries.
The plant consists of two fossil fueled steam turbine generators (Units 1 and 2) together with a newly installed simple cycle peaking unit (Unit 3). Unit 1 has a supercritical boiler and 4 casing steam turbine with a hydrogen cooled generator, which is capable of producing 521 MW. Unit 2 has a subcritical boiler with a three casing steam turbine and hydrogen generator, which can produce 560
MW.
Unit 3 is a GE Frame 7HA.02 combustion turbine generator which at 337 MW.
Units 1 and 2 were originally baseload units; they are now operated in peak capacity mode. Canal
Generating Station supplies 345 kV power via the adjacent Eversource switchyard.
Unit 1 uses No.6 oil as fuel, Unit 2 utilizes either No.6 oil or natural gas. Once Unit 3 is commercial it will use natural gas as a primary fuel with No.2 fuel oil as a back-up fuel.
Unit 3 is able to switch between natural gas and liquid fuel whilst online. This feature has been proven during commissioning in both directions at 30% load: natural gas to liquid fuel and liquid fuel to natural gas. Commissioning switchover demonstrations at 50% load have yet to be completed.
The plant gas supply is insufficient to operate both Units 2 and 3 on natural gas at the same time. It is anticipated that Unit 3 will be prioritized.
One of the drivers for the installation of Unit 3 was the imminent retirement of the nearby Pilgrim nuclear plant which is planned for May 31, 2019. Unit 3 is scheduled to be commercial by this date.
Unit Yea Boiler Turbine Generator r Manufacturer Manufacture Manufacture M Servic r r W e
1 1968 Babcock &amp; Wilcox Westinghouse Westinghouse 521 1969
2 1976 Babcock &amp; Wilcox Westinghouse Westinghouse 560 1976
3 2018 - GE GE 384 2019
Operating Status
Units 1 and 2 were not operating during the visit. Unit 3 was being commissioned and was shut down for a catalyst outage.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 12Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Risk Characteristics Ratings
Area Rated Rating Risk Reduction Suggestions/Comments
Major Equipment
Boilers G
Steam Turbines G
Combustion Turbines G
Generators G
Transformers G
Major Systems
High Energy Piping G
Feedwater and Condensate G
Water Treatment G
Operations
Control Room Review G
Operating Procedures and Training F Poor operations practices contributed to saltwater incursion.
Operational Testing G
Maintenance
Maintenance Management and Training F Two transformer failures.
Predictive Maintenance (PdM) G
Pressure Vessels G
Auxiliary Safety Valve Maintenance G
Electrical Maintenance G
Emergency Battery G
Excellent The facility has taken measures that exceed industry standards and best practices. Loss potential is considered significantly reduced.
GoodThe facility has taken measures that are consistent with industry standards and best practices. Loss potential is considered to be average.
FairThe facility has taken some measures that approach industry standards and best practices; however, deficiencies exist.
Loss potential is considered somewhat increased.
PoorThe facility has major deficiencies and does not approach industry standards and best practices. Loss potential is considered to be significantly increased.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 13Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Major Equipment
Boilers
Uni Yea t r Manufacturer LB/H MAW Primary Secondary P °F Fuel Fuel
Babcock &amp;
1 1969 Wilcox 3,720 3825 100 No.6 Fuel Oil -
Supercritical 0
2 1976 Babcock &amp; 100 Wilcox 4,002 2500 0 No.6 Fuel Oil Natural Gas
Additional Nameplate Information
Unit 1 has a B&amp;W once through supercritical double reheat boiler with 16 oil burner cells on the front wall and 8 on the rear wall. There are a total of 40 burners.
Unit 2 has a B&amp;W subcritical natural circulation drum type boiler with a balanced draft furnace. The boiler has16 burner cells on 2 levels (8 front wall and 8 rear wall).
Boiler Draft
Both boilers are balanced draft.
Boiler Protection
Boiler protection includes but is not limited to:
· Low Water Level Alarm
· Low/Low Water Level Trip
· High Water Level Alarm/Trip
· SH Temperature High/Low Alarm
· Boiler Feedwater Pressure Low Alarm
· Feedwater Flow Alarm (UP)/Trip
· Steam Flow Alarm (UP)/Trip
Drum Level Indication
Unable to verify type of indication during this visit.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 14Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Boiler Safety Valves
Safety valve testing is reportedly based on operating hours. Since the units rarely operate this is unsatisfactory. The last test was performed in 2016. Previously the valves were overhauled on a three year cycle.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 15Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Summary of Major Boiler Modifications and Design Changes
Unit 1
· In 1995 Riley installed Low NO burners and steam atomized low pressure burners. This resulted in a reduction of the fuel oil burner tip pressure from approximately 850 psig to a range between 50 and 200 psig.
· In addition, the burner management system was upgraded to Bailey Infi90 with Fire-eye flame scanners.
· In 2000 selective catalytic reduction (SCR) was installed.
Unit 2
· In 1996 Riley installed Low NO burners and steam atomized low pressure burners.
· In 2006 selective non-catalytic reduction (SNCR) was installed.
Summary of Major Boiler Maintenance
Annual boiler outages are conducted.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 16Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Steam Turbines
Uni Yea Manufacture M RP Pressur t r r W M e
1 1968 Westinghouse 521 3600 3825
2 1976 Westinghouse 560 3600 2500
Additional Nameplate Information
Unit 1 nameplate
Unit 1 is a four casing four exhaust double reheat condensing Westinghouse Building block unit. It has:
· BB46 VHP/HP casing and rotor Serial 13-A-3001-1
· BB57 IP casing and rotor Serial 13-A-3002-1
· 2 x BB73R Ruggedized LP casings and rotors; Serial 13-A-3003-1, 3-A-3004-1
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 17Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Unit 1 turbine and generator
Unit 1 has a shaft driven boiler feed pump, which is coupled to the outboard end of the VHP/HP rotor.
That can supply 50% of the boiler demand. The remaining 50% is provided by an electric feed pump.
Unit 1 shaft driven boiler feed pump
Unit 2 is a three casing 4 exhaust double reheat condensing Westinghouse unit. It has a HP/IP casing and rotor Serial 13-A-4411-1 and 2 x BB73R Ruggedized LP casings and rotors Serial 13-A-4412-1,
3-A-4413-1.
Unit 2 has a turbine boiler feed pump that can supply 50% of the boiler demand. The remaining 50% is provided by an electric feed pump.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 18Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Unit 2 Boiler feed pump and BFPT
Steam Turbine Protection
Turbine protection includes but is not limited to:
· Vibration Monitoring: Vibration Monitor – Alarm/Trip
· Overspeed Trip Protection: Mechanical/Electronic
· Sequential Trip Protection
· Low Lube Oil Pressure Alarm/Trip
· Low Lube Oil Temperature Alarm
· High Lube Oil Temperature Alarm
· Lube Oil Reservoir Level High/Low
· Axial Rotor Position/Thrust Trip
· High Exhaust Hood Temperature Trip
· Low Vacuum Alarm/Trip
· Emergency Oil Pump o Thermal Overloads to Alarm Only o Multiple Pressure Switches o Normally Energized Starting Circuit
· High Metal Temperature Alarm
· Low Vacuum Trip
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 19Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Shaft Grounding Device
The units have brush type grounding devices.
Turbine Water Induction Protection Systems (TWIPS)
This was not discussed during this visit.
Summary of Major Turbine Modifications and Design Changes
Unit 2 control system was upgraded in 2002 to Bailey Infi-90.
Summary of Major Steam Turbine Maintenance
The table below shows the limited amount of operation in recent years.
Because of the limited operation the units are placed on turning gear weekly.
Unit 2016 2017 2018
Starts Hours Starts Hours Starts Hours
1 2 60 2 66 5 205
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 20Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Unit 2016 2017 2018
Starts Hours Starts Hours Starts Hours
2 3 213 2 157 2 232
Unit 1
2015 Throttle Valve Repair
· Damaged Left side throttle valve repaired.
2012 LP L-0 Blade Inspection
· Last row blades inspected by Siemens. A visual and Eddy-Current inspection conducted with no adverse findings.
2008: HP and IP Turbine Outage
VHP/HP turbine:
· Complete replacement of HP rotor and inner shell.
· All HP stop and governor valves disassembled
IP turbine:
· Replacement of Gen End rotor blading
· Rotor bore examination
· All IP stop and governor valves disassembled.
· All IP seals replaced.
Unit 2
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 21Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
2015 Saltwater Incursion Outage
Due to a condenser leak the turbine and boiler were shut down for inspection and cleaning. The cause of the saltwater incursion was determined to be previously plugged tubes where the plugs failed due to freezing of water inside the tubes. The entire turbine was dismantled after the incident. Cleaning and inspections were conducted.
The LP turbine rotors were determined to be at risk due to SCC following the inspection. Two used rotors were purchased and will be installed in 2019.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 22Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Combustion Turbine
Unit Year Manufacturer MW Model
3 2017 General Electric 337 7HA.02
Additional Nameplate Information
Serial No. 299551; Unit is simple cycle with DLN and SCR (uses 19% aqueous ammonia).
Unit 3 has evaporative cooling at the inlet.
The CT is required to reach full load within ten minutes.
Combustion Turbine Protection
Combustion Turbine protection includes but is not limited to:
· Vibration Monitoring: Alarm &amp; Trip
· Overspeed Trip Protection: Electronic
· Axial Rotor Position/Thrust Trip
· High Lube Oil Temperature Alarm
· Hot Gas Temperature High Trip
· High Exhaust Gas Temperature Trip
· Loss of Flame Trip
· Low Lube Oil Pressure Trip
· Low Lube Oil Temperature Alarm
· High Lube Oil Temperature Alarm
· Anti-icing Logic/Trip
· GE Mk Vie Control System
Summary of Major Combustion Turbine Modifications and Design Changes
The unit was still being commissioned during the visit – no modifications.
Summary of OEM Bulletin Compliance
The unit is subject to a CSA with the OEM.
· GE Performs all non-remedial maintenance on Gas Turbine (flange to flange) and Mark VI control system
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 23Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
· GE performs scheduled Combustor, HGP and MI outages at known prices. Extra work at
T&amp;M rates
· GE implements all required TILs at its cost
· GE takes on cost risk of scheduled maintenance events that occur with greater than expected frequencies (i.e. Canal 3 pays for only 1 HGP and MI per 1,800 FFS or 50,000 FFH)
· GE performs annual (or more frequent) borescopes to ensure events can be planned
· GE maintains a $5M/$10M deductible to repair collateral damage (per event/year) in the event that such an unplanned event occurs
· Canal receives stipulated discounts from GE standard rates for additional parts, services and
T&amp;M rates
· Coverage thru first Major Inspection
So far the following TILs are known to have been completed.
TIL 2097 7HA STAGE ONE BUCKET SHANK DISTRESS – Row 1 blades replaced.
TIL 2094R1HA AXIAL FUEL STAGING (AFS) COMBUSTION MONITORING
Summary of Major Combustion Turbine Maintenance
No data available – unit still being commissioned.
Unit Type Inspection Intervals
Combustion Hot Gas Path Major
Inspection Inspection Inspection
Frame
7HA.02 10,000 25,000 50,000
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 24Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Generators
Uni Manufacture MV Voltag t r A Cooling e (kV)
1 Westinghouse 632 Hydroge n 18.0
2 Westinghouse 610 Hydroge n 18.0
3 GE ? Hydroge n ?
Additional Nameplate Information
Unit 2 Nameplate
Unit 1 Serial No. 1S-71P130
Unit 2 Serial No. 1S-80P370
Nameplate data for Unit 3 was not available
Generator Protection
Generator protection includes but is not limited to:
· Loss of Excitation/Field (40G)
· Under/Over Voltage (59G)
· Back-Up Distance (21G)
· Over Excitation (24G)
· Synchronization Check (25)
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 25Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
· Instantaneous Overcurrent (50)
· Differential (87G)
· Under/Over Frequency (81G)
· Time Overcurrent (51GN)
· Reverse/Directional Power (32G)
· Ground Differential (87G)
· Rotor/Field Ground Detection (64F)
· Negative Sequence Overcurrent (46G)
· Volts/Hertz (24)
· Out-of-Step Protection (78G)
· Neutral Ground Over Voltage (64G)
· Stator Winding Temperature Alarm
Retaining Rings
All retaining rings are made from 18Cr-18Mn material.
Hydrogen Conditioning
All generators have hydrogen dryers with dew point monitoring. Since all generators have water cooled stator windings, a Stator Leakage Monitoring System (SLMS) is also installed to monitor stator cooling water chemistry and hydrogen leakage into the cooling water.
Summary of Major Generator Modifications and Design Changes
No major changes were reported.
Summary of Major Generator Maintenance
No data available due to loss of access to NRG databases.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 26Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Transformers
Unit Yea r Manufacture r Ø Coolin g Method MV A Voltage (kV)
@@@ &gt; Unit
1 GSU
$$$

@@@ &gt; Yea r
2013
$$$

@@@ &gt; Manufacture r
HICO
$$$

@@@ &gt; Ø
3
$$$

@@@ &gt; Coolin g Method
N/A
$$$

@@@ &gt; MV A
576
$$$

@@@ &gt; Voltage (kV)
18/345
$$$

@@@ &gt; Unit
2 GSU A
$$$

@@@ &gt; Yea r
2014
$$$

@@@ &gt; Manufacture r
HICO
$$$

@@@ &gt; Ø
3
$$$

@@@ &gt; Coolin g Method
N/A
$$$

@@@ &gt; MV A
300
$$$

@@@ &gt; Voltage (kV)
18/345
$$$

@@@ &gt; Unit
2 GSU B
$$$

@@@ &gt; Yea r
1994
$$$

@@@ &gt; Manufacture r
GE
$$$

@@@ &gt; Ø
3
$$$

@@@ &gt; Coolin g Method
N/A
$$$

@@@ &gt; MV A
300
$$$

@@@ &gt; Voltage (kV)
18/345
$$$

@@@ &gt; Unit
3 GSU
$$$

@@@ &gt; Yea r
201
$$$

@@@ &gt; Manufacture r
?
$$$

@@@ &gt; Ø
3
$$$

@@@ &gt; Coolin g Method
N/A
$$$

@@@ &gt; MV A
?
$$$

@@@ &gt; Voltage (kV)
?
$$$

@@@ &gt; Unit
1 Station Service
$$$

@@@ &gt; Yea r
1999
$$$

@@@ &gt; Manufacture r
Pennsylvania
$$$

@@@ &gt; Ø
3
$$$

@@@ &gt; Coolin g Method
N/A
$$$

@@@ &gt; MV A
45
$$$

@@@ &gt; Voltage (kV)
17.1/4.1 6
$$$

Additional Nameplate Information
Unit 1 has a single GSU; Unit 2 has 2 GSUs in parallel.
Canal 1 Main GSU failed in October 2012
· Original installed transformer - failed without warning
· All Oil Sampling results didn’t indicate any performance related issues
· Unit entered into a Forced Outage during this time
· New transformer was procured and unit was returned to service in October 2013
Canal 2 Main 2A GSU failed in July 2013
· Original installed transformer - failed due to a bushing failure (water related)
· Unit entered into a Forced Derate (300 MW) during this time
· New transformer was procured and unit was returned to full load in May 2014
Unit 3 GSU could not be accessed to verify nameplate data.
Transformer Protection
Transformer protection includes but is not limited to:
· Sudden Pressure Relay (63)
· Buchholz Relay (33)
· Pressure Relief Device
· High and Low Oil Level Alarm
· Winding Temperature Alarm and Trip (49W)
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 27Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
· Oil Temperature Alarm and Trip (26Q)
· Ground Detection
· Lightning Arrestors
· Strike Counter
· Differential Relays (87)
· Overcurrent Relays (50/51)
· Continuous Gas Monitoring
Transformer Oil Analysis
DGA testing is performed semi-annually. No results were made available.
Summary of Transformer Maintenance
Electrical testing is performed on a five yearly cycle. No results were available.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 28Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Major Systems
High Energy Piping
Canal Generating Station does have a scheduled HEP inspection program. The program was developed by Thielsch Engineering.
The program encompasses main and reheat piping (hot and cold) as well as pipe hangers and FAC issues.
Historic reports were not available due to issues related to transition from the old plant owners NRG.
The next HEP inspection is scheduled for November of 2019.
Feedwater and Condensate
Deaerator/Feedwater Heater NDE Examination - The deaerators are constructed according to
ASME code from SA517 material. They are inspected visually every year and using wet fluorescent magnetic particle testing every 2 years. In 2014 minor crack indications were removed by grinding.
Boiler Feed Pumps - Unit 1 has a shaft driven boiler feed pump, which is coupled to the outboard end of the VHP/HP rotor that can supply 50% of the boiler demand. The remaining 50% is provided by an electric feed pump.
Unit 2 has a turbine boiler feed pump that can supply 50% of the boiler demand. The remaining 50% is provided by an electric feed pump.
Water Treatment
Since the 2015 saltwater incursion incident, the plant water treatment equipment and procedures have been overhauled. The plant now uses Anodamine for corrosion protection.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 29Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Operations
Control Room Review
The control room is located in between Units 1 and 2 attended 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.
Unit 1 controls are Bailey Infi90 for the boiler and Bailey ESTI.
Unit 2 controls are Bailey Infi90 for both boiler and steam turbine.
The newly installed Unit 3 will be operated from the existing control room using GE MkVI control system.
Operating Procedures
The plant recently changed hands (was previously NRG) procedures are under review by the new owners and may be subject to changes/updates.
Operator Training
The plant operators have to be certified by the state of Massachusetts. Canal has a good training program which includes mandatory simulator training requiring regular updates.
Operating staff received six weeks of training from GE as part of the installation of Unit 3.
Operational Testing
Overspeed Trip Testing
Overspeeds are scheduled to be performed annually; however, the reduced running time makes this difficult in practice.
Main Turbines – Unit 1 has both mechanical and electronic overspeed protection. The last mechanical test was performed in January 2018. The last electronic overspeed was conducted in
May 2017.
Unit 2 has both mechanical and electronic overspeed protection. The last mechanical test was
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 30Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station performed in July 2016. The last electronic overspeed was conducted in August 2017. The OEM,
Siemens has recommended to postpone any further overspeeds until the LP rotors have been replaced.
Boiler Feed Pump Turbines – Unit 2A boiler feed pump turbine was last trip tested in October
2017.
Turbine Valve Testing
Valve testing is performed during the rare start-ups of Units 1 and 2.
Generator Liquid Level Detector Testing
This is performed daily during operation.
Turbine Water Induction Protection Systems (TWIPS)
This was not discussed during visit.
Emergency Lube and Seal Oil Pump Testing
The emergency lube and seal was tested during operation.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 31Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Maintenance
Maintenance Management
The plant appears to be adequately staffed for maintenance activities. NAES have upgraded to MAXIMO for maintenance planning. Work orders are produced automatically based on running hours of the equipment.
Maintenance Training
Most of the plant maintenance personnel have been at the facility for more than 10 years. Through in- house training supplemented by OEM programs, they have achieved a good level of competency.
Predictive Maintenance (PdM)
Thermographic Inspection
The plant has a thermographic historically used for surveys of electrical equipment. Since NAES have taken over the O&amp;M contract, they have been using a contractor for this work.
Vibration Monitoring and Analysis
This was not discussed during visit.
Lube Oil Analysis
Analysis of lubricating oil and control fluids is performed on a quarterly basis. No reports were available for review during the visit.
Pressure Vessels
Not discussed during visit
Auxiliary Safety Valve Maintenance
This was not discussed during visit.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 32Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Electrical Maintenance
Protective Relays and Circuit Breakers
The plant tests all protective relays and breakers in accordance with NERC regulations. The most recent tests were performed in November 2018. Results were not made available during the visit.
Emergency Battery
Battery maintenance is performed in accordance with IEEE 450-2010 and NERC guidelines. Test results were not made available for review during the visit.
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 33Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Loss History
In the last five years or so there have been a number of losses at the Canal Generating Station:
Unit 1 Saltwater Incursion Outage 2015
Due to a condenser leak the turbine and boiler were shut down for inspection and cleaning. The cause of the saltwater incursion was determined to be previously plugged tubes where the plugs failed due to freezing of water inside the tubes. The entire turbine was dismantled after the incident. Cleaning and inspections were conducted.
The LP turbine rotors were determined to be at risk due to SCC following the inspection. Two used rotors were purchased and will be installed in 2019.
A comprehensive root cause analysis was performed. Based on the results of this process a number of shortcomings related to instrumentation and human elements were identified. An action plan was developed and instigated.
Unit2 Main 2A GSU failed in July 2013
· Original installed transformer - failed due to a bushing failure (water related)
· Unit entered into a Forced Derate (300 Mw) during this time
· New transformer was procured and unit was returned to full load in May 2014
· Unit 2B GSU is planned to be refurbished in November 2019
Unit 1 Main GSU failed in October 2012
· Original installed transformer - failed without warning
· All Oil Sampling results didn’t indicate any performance related issues
· Unit entered into a Forced Outage during this time
· New transformer was procured and unit was returned to service in October 2013
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 34Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Loss Estimates
Probable Maximum Loss (PML)
PD PML Calculation
The PML scenario is a last stage blade loss from a steam turbine resulting in damage to the turbine and hydrogen cooled generator.
PML Machinery Damage Estimate $35,000,000
The PML is defined as the physical damage and time loss expected to occur assuming the failure of a primary operating control and the failure of at least one safety or protective device. In addition, the affected equipment experiences a delayed shutdown or isolation. The PML is calculated using a percentage of the equipment value and is expressed as a specific total dollar amount. The figures do not take into consideration deductibles or sublimits.
BI PML Calculation
Based on an blade failure it is estimated that the unit would be unavailable for 6 months
PML Business Interruption Estimate 560 MW x 24 hours per day x 180 days =
(Does not take into account the capacity factor) 2,419,200 MWh
Maximum Foreseeable Loss (MFL)
PD MFL Calculation
The MFL scenario is an explosion of the Unit 1 supercritical boiler resulting in significant boiler damage and resulting damage to adjacent plant.
MFL Machinery Damage Estimate $180,000,000
The MFL is defined as the maximum amount of physical damage and time loss expected to occur under the worst possible conditions. This is based on the failure of operating controls and safety or protective devices with no shutdown or isolation of affected equipment. The MFL assumes this equipment operates to destruction. The MFL is calculated using a percentage of the equipment value and is expressed as a specific total dollar amount. The figures do not take into consideration deductibles or sublimits.
BI MFL Calculation
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 35Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station
Based on a complete loss of the supercritical boiler it is expected Unit 1 would be unavailable for a year.
MFL Business Interruption Estimate 560 MW x 24 hours per day x 365 days =
(Does not take into account the capacity factor) 4,905,600 MWh
AEGIS Insurance Services, Inc. 36Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings LLC
Machinery Underwriting Survey Canal Generating Station</text><riskFactors><entry><key>RF001</key><value name="RF001" value="E"><sentences><s riskFactorValue="E" begin="24293" end="24332"><text>DGA testing is performed semi-annually.</text><operands><op begin="24293" end="24296"><text>DGA</text></op><op begin="24297" end="24304"><text>testing</text></op><op begin="24308" end="24317"><text>performed</text></op><op begin="24323" end="24331"><text>annually</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="E" begin="24400" end="24455"><text>Electrical testing is performed on a five yearly cycle.</text><operands><op begin="24400" end="24410"><text>Electrical</text></op><op begin="24411" end="24418"><text>testing</text></op><op begin="24442" end="24448"><text>yearly</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="G" begin="27565" end="27657"><text>Boiler Feed Pump Turbines – Unit 2A boiler feed pump turbine was last trip tested in October</text><operands><op begin="27626" end="27629"><text>was</text></op><op begin="27635" end="27639"><text>trip</text></op><op begin="27640" end="27646"><text>tested</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="G" begin="28654" end="28738"><text>The plant has a thermographic historically used for surveys of electrical equipment.</text><operands><op begin="28664" end="28667"><text>has</text></op><op begin="28670" end="28683"><text>thermographic</text></op><op begin="28706" end="28713"><text>surveys</text></op></operands></s></sentences></value></entry><entry><key>RF002</key><value name="RF002" value="U"><sentences/></value></entry><entry><key>RF003</key><value name="RF003" value="F"><sentences><s riskFactorValue="X" begin="27927" end="27967"><text>Emergency Lube and Seal Oil Pump Testing</text><operands><op begin="27937" end="27941"><text>Lube</text></op><op begin="27946" end="27950"><text>Seal</text></op><op begin="27951" end="27954"><text>Oil</text></op></operands></s></sentences></value></entry><entry><key>RF004</key><value name="RF004" value="E"><sentences><s riskFactorValue="U" begin="12570" end="12624"><text>Unable to verify type of indication during this visit.</text><operands><op begin="12570" end="12576"><text>Unable</text></op><op begin="12580" end="12586"><text>verify</text></op><op begin="12580" end="12586"><text>verify</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="E" begin="27686" end="27756"><text>Valve testing is performed during the rare start-ups of Units 1 and 2.</text><operands><op begin="27686" end="27691"><text>Valve</text></op><op begin="27692" end="27699"><text>testing</text></op><op begin="27724" end="27728"><text>rare</text></op></operands></s></sentences></value></entry><entry><key>RF005</key><value name="RF005" value="E"><sentences><s riskFactorValue="E" begin="1306" end="1337"><text>Predictive Maintenance (PdM) 23</text><operands><op begin="1306" end="1328"><text>Predictive Maintenance</text></op><op begin="1330" end="1333"><text>PdM</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="E" begin="10750" end="10780"><text>Predictive Maintenance (PdM) G</text><operands><op begin="10750" end="10772"><text>Predictive Maintenance</text></op><op begin="10774" end="10777"><text>PdM</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="G" begin="19351" end="19526"><text>· GE takes on cost risk of scheduled maintenance events that occur with greater than expected frequencies (i.e. Canal 3 pays for only 1 HGP and MI per 1,800 FFS or 50,000 FFH)</text><operands><op begin="19378" end="19399"><text>scheduled maintenance</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="E" begin="28406" end="28495"><text>Most of the plant maintenance personnel have been at the facility for more than 10 years.</text><operands><op begin="28424" end="28435"><text>maintenance</text></op><op begin="28436" end="28445"><text>personnel</text></op></operands></s><s riskFactorValue="E" begin="28600" end="28628"><text>Predictive Maintenance (PdM)</text><operands><op begin="28600" end="28622"><text>Predictive Maintenance</text></op><op begin="28624" end="28627"><text>PdM</text></op></operands></s></sentences></value></entry><entry><key>RF006</key><value name="RF006" value="U"><sentences/></value></entry><entry><key>RF007</key><value name="RF007" value="F"><sentences><s riskFactorValue="X" begin="27927" end="27967"><text>Emergency Lube and Seal Oil Pump Testing</text><operands><op begin="27927" end="27936"><text>Emergency</text></op><op begin="27946" end="27950"><text>Seal</text></op></operands></s></sentences></value></entry><entry><key>RF008</key><value name="RF008" value="U"><sentences/></value></entry><entry><key>RF009</key><value name="RF009" value="U"><sentences/></value></entry><entry><key>RF010</key><value name="RF010" value="U"><sentences/></value></entry><entry><key>RF011</key><value name="RF011" value="U"><sentences/></value></entry><entry><key>RF012</key><value name="RF012" value="U"><sentences/></value></entry></riskFactors><parameters/><attributes><a name="CITY" begin="142" end="154"><text>Sandwich</text></a><a name="ZIP_CODE" begin="155" end="160"><text>02563</text></a><a name="LOCATION_NAME" begin="97" end="126"><text>Canal Generating Plant Unit 3</text></a><a name="INSURED_NAME" begin="70" end="96"><text>Stonepeak Kestrel Holdings</text></a><a name="INSURED_NAME" begin="0" end="8"><text>Rev. 1.0</text></a><a name="INSURED_NAME" begin="26" end="55"><text>Machinery Underwriting Survey</text></a><a name="STREET" begin="127" end="141"><text>9 Freezer Road</text></a><a name="SURVEY_DATE_WEAK" begin="161" end="175"><text>20190425</text></a><a name="AS_Presence" begin="0" end="1"><text>No</text></a></attributes></riskFactorAnalysis>